准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
游泳痴
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
动画总监
分镜指导
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我现在脸朝下地浮在一座游泳池里
Well, here I am floating face-down in a swimming pool
我一直都很想有座泳池
I always wanted a pool
最后  我也拥有了
and in the end, I got one
我是如何走到这地步的
How did I get here?
一切都要从昨天说起
Well, it all started yesterday
海绵
Sponge--
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
章鱼哥  你刚刚有说话吗
Squidward, did you say something?
你为什么要在你院子里挖坑
Why are you digging up your yard?
我在挖泳池
I'm putting in a pool
泳池
A pool?
而且我要邀请我最爱的隔壁邻居
And I'm going to invite my favorite next-door neighbor
挖完了就来一起玩
as soon as it's ready
别碰我
Get off me
我才不进去你的细菌滋生的大泥坑里
I wouldn't be caught dead
in your muddy, little bacteria hole
我只游高级的泳池
I only swim in sophisticated pools
如果你反悔想进来游的话
Well, if you change your mind
泳池就快挖好了
it's almost done
好  行
Yeah, sure
挖好了
It's done
什么
What the--?
真是好美啊
Why, it's beautiful
凭什么他就能有泳池
Why does he get to have a pool?
有资格拥有泳池的人
If anyone around here deserves a pool
必须是我
it's me
炮来了
Cannonball
章鱼哥  快进泳池里跟我们一起玩
Hey, Squidward, come join us in the pool
快  趁水还湿着进来玩
Quick, while the water's still wet
池子
Pool
忘了泳池
Forget the pool
怎么
What the--?
池子
Pool
安静点  泡消毒泳池水的大烂泥
Keep quiet, you chlorinated clods
炮来了
Cannonball
还游什么潮得要死的泳池
Who needs a soggy, old pool
明明都有高贵无比的
when you have the luxury and elegance
室内空调可以吹
of indoor air conditioning
有点热啊
It's a little hot
池子太酷了  痴子
That is one cool pool, my fool
明天见  海绵宝宝
See you tomorrow, SpongeBob
一路游泳平安  派大星
Swim safely, Patrick
泳池再见
Meet you at the pool
太热了
It's so hot
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
什么
What?
谁说的话
Who said that?
不要怂
Don't be a drip
过来游
Take a dip
你一定很想进来游
You know you want to
海绵宝宝睡着了
SpongeBob is asleep
快点游个泳凉快一下
I'll just take a quick dip to cool off
真乖
That a boy
跳进来
Jump in
池子
Pool
感谢海神王  没人听到
Thank Neptune nobody heard me
小蜗  放过海兔子
Gary, you leave those sea bunnies alone
快回来睡觉
and come to bed
现在我能一个人独占泳池了
Now I can have the pool all to myself
池子啊
Oh, pool
大家好啊
Ciao, everybody
章鱼哥好
Ciao, Squidwardo
章鱼哥  一定要给我们来吹个竖笛
Squidwardo, you must play your clarinet for us
务必来一首
You simply must
我考虑一下
I'll think about it
你好  美人儿
Ciao bella
什么
Wha--
完蛋  我一定是睡着了
Egad, I must've fallen asleep
不能让他们发现我在这
I can't let them find me here
等不及要玩水了
I can't wait to get wet
泳池玩具在哪
Where's the pool toys?
别进泳池小屋
Not the pool shed
都放在泳池小屋里了  笨蛋
They're in the pool shed, silly
躲起来
Gotta hide
玩具
Toys
我先来
Me first
好吧  派大星
Okay, Patrick
你先来挑玩具
You can pick first
哪个玩具
Which toy?
别挑我
Not me
就挑这个又大又丑的好了
I'll take this big, ugly one
软塌塌的  浮不起来
It's too floppy to float on
得要充个气
It needs more air
这样应该就行了
Well, that ought to do it
挑得不错  派大星
Nice find, Patrick
炮来坐了
Cannon sit
泳池大战
Pool fight
泳池
A pool--
坏掉了
It's broken
乘风破浪
Ride the wave
向后拉
Tug it back
向前拉
Tug it forth
向后拉
Tug it back
向前拉
Tug it forth
海绵宝宝  你看这个
SpongeBob, watch this
救命
Help me
黑洞
Black hole
再来再来
Again, again
是我
It's me
我就是泳池玩具  两个笨蛋
I was the pool toy, you idiots
章鱼哥
Squidward
这是我见过最神奇的魔术了
that's the greatest magic trick I've ever seen
对  再变一次吧
Yeah, let's do it again
听好  海绵宝宝
Look, SpongeBob
我承认了
I admit it
我没经过你同意就在你泳池里玩
I used your pool without permission
因为我特别嫉妒
because I'm really jealous of it
我想要你的泳池椅
I want your pool chairs
我想要你的泳池喷气口
I want your pool jets
我想要你的泳池浮条
I want your pool noodles
而且我最想要的就是这个跳水板
And most of all, I want this diving board
章鱼哥  我们是最棒的邻居
Squidward, we're best neighbors
你随时都可以来我泳池里玩
You can use my pool anytime you like
白天晚上都行  笨蛋
day or night, you silly
谢谢海绵宝宝
Thanks SpongeBob
你想不想来
Say, how'd you like to
上小板板来跳水水
take a divey-wivey on the boardy-woardy, hmm?
免了  就先不用了
Oh, no, thanks, but I just couldn't
请你务必要来跳水  章鱼哥
Please, you must take a dive, Squidwardo
那我就来跳水了
I would love to take a dive
我高中可是加了游泳队的
I was on my high school swim team
章鱼哥  这架梯子可以调
Hey, Squidward, this ladder is adjustable
要调高吗
Do you want to go higher?
我也爱你们大家
I love you all too
好  那就当你要调高了
Okay, I'll take that as a yes
调高吧  派大星
Crank it up, Patrick
你好  美人儿
Ciao bella
我跳了
I dive
实在太高了
Troppo elevato
太高了  太高了
Too high, too high
太高了  派大星
It's too high, Patrick
调低点
Crank it down
什么动静
What was that?
好耶
Yeah
完美一跳  章鱼哥
Perfect dive, Squidward
于是我便走到了这个地步
And that's how I got here
果不其然
Typical
高伯教父
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
你的餐好了  海霸王先生
Your order is ready, Mr. Bass
你把蟹黄堡
You've mingled Krabby Patty
混进了我的海草奶昔
in my kelp shake
抱歉  我帮你再打一杯奶昔
Sorry, let me refresh that for you
你先别急
Hold your seahorses
这东西既油腻  又清凉
It's greasy, yet cool and refreshing
马上再给我来一杯
Fetch me another posthaste
卖相好像不错
That does look good
我也想来一杯
I want one too
我感应到了赚钱的良机
I sense a money-tunity
菜单
全新蟹堡冰奶油  正在供应中
The brand-new Patty Whip is now on the menu
蟹堡冰奶油
适度付点巨款即可购买
available for a moderately exorbitant upcharge
好耶
Yep
能点两份打包外带吗
Can I get two to-go?
两份打包外带
Two to-go please
加把劲多做蟹堡冰奶油  章鱼哥先生
Keep those Patty Whips coming, Mr. Squidward
在加把劲了
I'm trying
蟹堡王
打烊了
Closing time
明天再来
See you tomorrow
终于啊
Finally
明天再过来  吃到你动脉硬化
You can harden your arteries tomorrow
我们已经关门了
We're closed
高伯教父想要
The Goobfather would like to have
跟你们老板谈个话
a little talk with your boss
高伯教父
Goobfather?
你不是高菲高伯的经理吗
Aren't you the manager of the Goofy Goober?
那只是我的正职
That's just my day job
高伯教父才是我的真实身份
The Goobfather is my true identity
我控制着全裤头村的冰淇淋贸易
I control all the ice cream trade in this town
而且还听说了你家在卖泄堡病油
and I heard about your little fatty flips
蟹堡冰奶油
是蟹堡冰奶油
That's Patty Whips
一点点良性竞争
And a little friendly competition
不会有事的
never hurt anyone
那当然了
Of course not
不过你们还是只做蟹黄堡比较好
but maybe you should stick to flipping patties
冷饮业务就交给专家  好不好
and leave the frozen treats to the experts, hm?
我新找到的摇钱树不能就这么断了
I'm not gonna stop selling my newest moneymaker
小的们  动手吧
Do your stuff, boys
什么
What?
妈妈  我想唱歌
Mama, I want to sing
你得谢谢我没让你变冰淇淋
Be thankful I didn't turn you into gelato
真好笑  老板
Good one, boss
卖不了蟹堡冰奶油了
No more Patty Whips
不用怕  小子
Don't worry, boyo
我的餐厅我做主
This is me restaurant
只有我能决定蟹堡王该卖什么
And no one tells me what's on me menu but me
蟹堡冰奶油机  又重新启动了
The Patty Whip machine, is working again
我一整晚都在重建这个机器
I spent all night rebuilding it
蟹堡冰奶油正式回归供应
Patty Whips are back on the menu
可是蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
要是高伯教父
what if the Goobfather
带着高伯暴徒手下回来怎么办
and his goober goons come back?
放心好了
Don't worry
我给蟹堡王加了点安保措施
I brought in a little protection meself
出来吧  小的们
Come on out, boys
他们是不是有点
Aren't they a little, uh
老了
elderly?
我们皱纹可能是多了点
We may be a little wrinkly
但我们身体还硬朗着
But we're as tough as jerky
死定了
We're dead
高伯教父想再找你们谈个话
The Goobfather would like to have another little talk
这不是那位不听话的螃蟹吗
Well, if it isn't the crab who don't listen
再教训教训他  小的们
Teach him another lesson, boys
你先别急  高伯教父
Not so fast, Goobfather
把那些来捣乱的扔出蟹堡王
Throw these interloper out of me restaurant
开始排成42号阵型
Initiate formation 42
快看
Look
那边是不是有指虎大促销
Is that a sale on brass knuckles?
指虎
Brass knuckles?
有适合我的尺寸吗
Do they have my size?
抱歉
Sorry
该开溜了
Time to skedaddle
这俩暴徒身手不错
These goons are good
不
No
我们被打成奶油了
Well, we're whipped
下次招几个壮一点的打手  老螃蟹
Next time you hire some muscle, Krabs
得有肌肉的才行
make sure they have muscles
吃花生吧  傻瓜蛋
Eat goobers, you goofballs
都闹够了
Enough of this bilge water
得去高伯教父的地盘亲手较量一下了
Time to take the fight to the Goobfater's home turf
高菲高伯
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry
抱歉
Sorry
找找破坏后能产生严重影响的东西
Keep your eye open for anything worth sabotaging
我说你呢
Hey, you
你说我吗
Who, me?
给我两大球
Give me a double scoop
海草漩涡  多加彩糖粒
of kelp swirl with extra sprinkles
马上就来
Coming up
两球海草漩涡  多加彩糖粒
Double K swirl and make it snow
就破坏那个调温器了
That thermostat, that'll do
现在得转移别人注意力
Now all we need is a distraction
你放心  蟹老板
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs
包在我身上
I've got it handled
哒哒
Ta-da
好耶
Oh, yeah
来看我
Check me out
实在太逊了
It's so lame
可我就是目不转睛想看他
but I can't take my eyes off the guy
我打心里感受到了他冰淇淋勺的律动
I can feel the rhythm of his scoops in my soul
这段比较难
This is the tricky part
这样一定会让他们雪糕化掉
This'll sizzle their sorbet
大家跟上节奏
Try and keep up, y'all
我的冰淇淋勺着火了
My scoops are on fire
他的勺子好有火热的节奏
His funky scoops are so smokin' hot
都让我流汗了
I'm sweating
火热的不是勺子
It's not his spoons
是有人把温度调高了
Someone's turned up the heat
冰淇淋会有严重安全隐患
The ice cream is going critical
完成
Big finish
走了  小子
Come on, kid
现在该逃出这家冰淇淋店了
It's time to blow this ice cream stand
趁冰淇淋店还没炸赶紧跑
before this ice cream stand blows
该开溜了  小子
Time to cheese it, boyo
跟老海军作对  有你好受的
Never mess with an old Navy man
我会逮到你的  老螃蟹
I'll get you, Krabs
你家海绵也照样逮
and your little sponge too
准备好受死吧
Prepare to be annihilated
蟹老板  高伯教父来了
Mr. Krabs, it's the Goobfather
竞争对手餐厅要撞上我们了
We're about to be hit by a competing restaurant
放心  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob
已经做好反击准备了
we're ready for 'em
部署软冰淇淋炮
Deploy soft serve cannons
激活太妃糖履带
Activate toffee treads
热奶糖榴弹炮
Hot fudge howitzer
启动引擎  小子
Try the engines, boyo
遵命  蟹老板
Aye, aye, Mr. Krabs
发射冰淇淋炮
Fire ice cream cannons
正在发射冰淇淋炮
Firing ice cream cannons
避开炮弹
Evasive maneuvers
开火反击
Return fire
开冰淇淋反击
Return ice cream
吃我两大球
Have a double scoop
脑子冻住了
Brain freeze
吃我热奶糖  坏蛋
Eat hot fudge, villain
疼得又黏又美味
Such sticky yet delicious pain
别忘了撒彩糖粒
Don't forget the sprinkles
发射甜筒无人机
Launch sugar cone drones
我要把你送进冰柜里  老螃蟹
I'm sending you to the deep freeze, Krabs
你做梦  高伯教父
In your ice dreams, Goobfather
奶糖
Fudge
绝不投降
Not giving up
我也不投降
Me neither
那是什么声音
What's that sound?
不会吧
It couldn't be
冰淇淋大王
The Ice Cream King
放下你们的第一
Cease your hostil-lily--
敌意
hostile--
不要再打了
quit fightin'
冰淇淋不能用来打架
Ice cream isn't meant for brawling
应该为世界带来糖分搭建的乐趣
It's supposed to bring sugar-built fun
让所有人肚子疼  冻脑袋
belly aches, and brain freezes to the world
他说得对
He's right
我们不该大打出手
We shouldn't be fighting
有不少白痴
There's plenty of saps--
或者说  客人
or, customers in town
可以由我们服务
for both of us
如果你们还要继续打下去
And if you don't quit fighting
我就要使出我的终极武器
I'll use my ultimate weapon
冰淇淋炸弹
the ice cream bomb
Ice cream bomb?
等等
Wait
我们已经不打了
We've already stopped fighting
什么
What?
我听不见
I can't hear you
等下  我马上下来
Hold on, I'll be right down
投弹
Bombs away
大家快来吃免费冰淇淋
Hey, everyone, free ice cream
我在做梦吗
Is this a dream?
一辈子都有免费冰淇淋
Free ice cream forever
不用谢
You're welcome
看来我们都被迫停业了
It looks like we're all out of business
谁来帮忙放我下来
Will someone please get me down?
果不其然
Typical